Guide to the Henry S. Cross Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Henry S. Cross papers
1900-1932
1925-1932
SC0648
Cross, Henry S.
1 Linear feet
Collection pertains largely to his student life at Stanford University. Included are programs of events he attended, 1927-1932; expense records, 1927-1932; his class registration cards; student handbook, 1928/29 and other Stanford publications; dance cards from dances at Castilleja School (Palo Alto), Stanford, and other places, 1925-31; and photographs. Among the photographs are shots of Cross on campus and in his dorm room, building the 1930 bonfire structure, the play "Wings over Europe" at Stanford, 1931, and other family and unidentified images, including two images of a hiking group ca. 1900.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchased from Gregory H. Bock, 2002.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Henry Settle Cross, Jr. earned his A.B. in social sciences at Stanford University in 1932. As a student, he was active in drama productions.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains largely to his student life at Stanford University. Included are programs of events he attended, 1927-1932; expense records, 1927-1932; his class registration cards; student handbook, 1928/29 and other Stanford publications; dance cards from dances at Castilleja School (Palo Alto), Stanford, and other places, 1925-31; and photographs. Among the photographs are shots of Cross on campus and in his dorm room, building the 1930 bonfire structure, the play "Wings over Europe" at Stanford, 1931, and other family and unidentified images, including two images of a hiking group ca. 1900.
Access Terms
Bock, Gregory H.; Castilleja School.; Cross, Henry S.; Big Game bonfire.; College students--California.; Dance cards.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Big Game 1930 – ticket and instruction for rooters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calling cards and place cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commencement 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Expense records, 1927-29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Expense records, 1930-32 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Greeting cards (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hoover pin/clip (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: negatives of beach party (no prints) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: football (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: hiking group ca. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: miscellaneous (unidentified individuals, choir, group) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: portraits of Henry S. Cross, Jr. and other unidentified men (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: Stanford (1930 bon fire, Cross on campus, Cross in dorm room) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: theater ("Wings over Europe" 1931 and unidentified) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Programs, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Programs, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Programs, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Programs, no date (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Registration cards and miscellaneous forms (S.U.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - San Francisco News – special on Herbert Hoover, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stanford University publications (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Student handbook, 1928/29 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dance cards, Castilleja School, Dec. 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dance cards, Castilleja School, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dance cards, Castilleja School, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dance cards, Castilleja School, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dance card, Junior-Senior, Country Club, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dance cards, parties, 1925-28 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dance card, Pomona College, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dance card, Scott House formal, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dance cards, Stanford, 1927, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dance cards, unidentified, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dance cards, unidentified, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)